A Guide to the Documents from the County Manager's Library, 1889-1994
Arlington Public Library, Center for Local History
Arlington Public Library, Center for Local History
Documents from the County Manager's Library, 1889-1994
Arlington Public Library, Center for Local History
RG 32
100 boxes.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
The collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
Nearly all the materials in Record Group 32 came from an in-county transfer in 1981 from the County Manager's Office to Arlington Public Library. Some scattered documents from 1982 to 1990, and 2004 were received later and added to the collection.
Historical Information
The County Manager's Library was formally established from these informal holdings through a student's thesis for a Library Science Master's Degree: A Proposed Plan for the Organization and Administration of a Reference Library for the County-Manager Government of Arlington County by Marcel Raymond Gerin, The Catholic University of America, December 1959.
Mr. Gerin set up the library for the County and processed all the materials in a cataloging system (See Subgroup 19). After the library was disbanded in 1981, the materials were sent to the Arlington County Public Library and the Center for Local History. The materials saved for this record group were mostly County-generated. Other items expected to be available elsewhere were excluded.
Scope and Content
Record Group 32 contains materials gathered by various Arlington County managers and housed in their quasi-professional library existing from 1932, the year when the county manager form of government was adopted, until 1981. The collection consists largely of county-generated reports and other documents which the managers may have referred to over the years as they administered county business.
This collection is not a comprehensive grouping of materials from any particular time period. Rather it is simply whatever the managers might have gathered during their time in office and placed on their shelves. The materials date from 1889 to 1994, with the bulk dating from 1930 to 1981. The collection measures about 60 linear feet.
In this collection, there are almost complete County Board meeting minutes and agendas from 1932-1952 (excluding 1950) and the spring of 1957, and county budgets and audits for those years. There is also extensive documentation on the county's infrastructure, including road construction, traffic studies, sewage and water systems, and planning and development. Subgroup 7, County Manager Personal Files, has handwritten notes by various County Managers on a variety of subjects, arranged chronologically. That subgroup also contains County Attorney opinions from the 1930s and 1940s. Subgroup 20, Advisory Groups, has material from various groups throughout Arlington who provided advice and information on a wide variety of topics related to county government.
Arrangement
Record Group 32 is arranged by subject or county agency into subgroups under which listings are largely chronological. Most photographs were removed from their original locations in the collection and moved to a special box, Box 93. A list of these photographs is in the appendix, with a list of each photograph's original location. The appendix also lists the collection's bound materials, which are mainly annual reports and budgets. The only photographs that remain in their original folders are those found in the Police Traffic Safety Reports in Subgroup 5, Series 3. These photographs remain to show their placement within these larger reports.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Researchers interested in issues revolving around the development of National Airport should consult Record Group 13, Samuel Milner National Airport Research Papers, Record Group 37, Metropolitan Washington Airports, and RG 189, Anderson National Airport Collection. Researchers interested in Arlington planning and construction should consult RG 43, Interstate 66, RG 199, Papers of Carrie Johnson, and RG 130, Arlington County Planning Commission Records. Those reviewing public health in Arlington should look at RG 21, Records of the Arlington County Department of Health and RG 169, Records of the School Nurse Program. For more information on Arlington Fire Department, see RG 170, Personal Papers of James Fought. More formal county government publications are found in RG 58, Arlington County Government Publications.
Digital scans of many of the photographs in RG 32 can be found here.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Arlington Co., Va. County Manager; Arlington County (Va.) -- Politics and government.; Arlington County (Va.). Planning Division; Fire departments -- Administration; Arlington County (Va.). Police Department; Civil defense; Arlington County (Va.). Department of Public Works; Arlington County (Va.). Department of Environmental Affairs; Arlington (Va.); Arlington County (Va.)
Contents List
- Planning
  - Apartments
    - Rent Stabilization Facts, 1952 (Box 1)
    - Apartment Developments by Census Tracts (4 pubs), 1956, 1961, 1963, 1965 (Box 1)
    - Apartment Seekers Guides, 1975, 1976, 1979, 1981 (Box 1)
    - Your Rights and Responsibilities, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Aurora Hills Center
    - Specifications, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Buildings, Public
    - Preliminary Public Buildings Report, 1959 (Box 1)
    - Public Buildings, 1960 (Box 1)
    - Proposed Cultural-Ed Center, Iterim Report, 1965 (Box 1)
    - Proposed Cultural-Ed Center, Study, 1967 (Box 1)
    - Arlington Arts Center, Part 1, Prospectus, 1974 (Box 1)
    - Arlington Arts Center, Part 2, Feasibility, 1974 (Box 1)
    - Arlington Arts Center, Part 3, Econ Analysis, 1974 (Box 1)
    - Arlington Arts Center, Part 4, The Arts in Arlington, 1974 (Box 1)
  - Buildings, Office
    - Report on Office Buildings, 1953 (Box 1)
    - Commercial and Professional Office Buildings, 1961 (Box 1)
    - Arlington's Office Space Industry, 1965 (Box 1)
    - Office Buildings, 1968 (Box 2)
    - Office Building Directory (2 docs), 1979-80 (Box 2)
    - Trends in Office & Commercial Development, 1985 (Box 2)
  - Capital Improvement
    - Capital Improvement Program Report, 1946 (Box 2)
    - Capital Improvement Program, 1947 (Box 2)
    - Report of Long-Range Capital Improvement Committee, 1957-1958 (Box 2)
    - Departmental Requests on Capital Improvements, 1958-59 (Box 2)
    - Arlington County's Next Decade - Fiscal Projection, 1959 (draft, final & 1960 reprint) (Box 2)
    - Arlington County's Next Decade - Capital Improvement Projection, 1960 (Box 2)
    - Toward, 1980 ( 1974 ) (Box 2)
    - Public Finance 2, 1975 (Box 2)
    - Five-Year Capital Improvement Program, 1973-77 (Box 2)
    - Capital Improvement Program, 1978-82 (Box 2)
    - Capital Improvement Program, 1980-85 (Box 2)
    - Capital Improvement Program, 1983-88 (Box 2)
    - Capital Improvement Program, 1987-92 (Box 3)
  - Cherrydale
    - Commercial Area Study, 1958 (Box 3)
    - Supplement: Commercial District, Revised, 1961 (Box 3)
  - Clarendon
    - Commercial District, 1958 (Box 3)
    - Physical Development 4, 1975 (Box 3)
  - Clarendon-Ballston
    - Commercial Districts, Part 1 1958 (Box 3)
    - Commercial Districts, Part 2 1958 (Box 3)
    - Commercial Districts, Part 3 1958 (Box 3)
    - Real Estate Investment Feasibility, 1961 (Box 3)
  - Colonial Village
    - Environmental Considerations Report, 1979 (Box 3)
  - Columbia Pike
    - Commercial District, 1958 (Box 3)
    - West Commercial District, 1959 (Box 3)
  - Commercial Districts
    - Three Districts: Arlington Forest Shopping Center; S. Abington St.; S. Carlin Springs Rd., 1959 (Box 3)
  - Commercial Studies
    - Various Businesses, 1960 (Box 3)
    - Summary Report, 1960 (Box 3)
  - Court House
    - Space Requirements, 1956 (Box 3)
    - Improvements, 1957 (Box 3)
    - Master Plan, 1987 (Box 4)
  - Development Controls
    - Legal Potentials & Constraints, 1975 (Box 4)
  - East Falls Church
    - Commercial and Industrial District, 1958 (Box 4)
  - Economics
    - Economic Data (VA Department of Conservation & Development), 1953 (Box 4)
    - People, Land and Livelihood, 1959 (Box 4)
    - Arlington's Economic Status, 1961 (Box 4)
    - Economic Fact Book, 1978 (Box 4)
  - Glebe Road
    - Ballston to Columbia Pike Commercial Areas, 1959 (Box 4)
  - Goernment Center
    - Development Program, 1954 (Box 4)
    - Judicial Center Program Study: Master Planning Implications, 1970 (Box 4)
  - Growth
    - Potentials for Growth in Arlington County, 1971 (Box 4)
    - Implications of Alternative Growth Patterns, 1972 (Box 4)
    - Growth Patterns: Profile, 1974 (Box 4)
    - Transit Station Impact Analysis, 1974 (Box 5)
    - Growth Patterns, Addenda Reports, 1975 (Box 5)
  - Housing
    - Character & Quality of Large-Scale Housing Projects, 1940 (Box 5)
    - Population & Housing by Census Tract, 1965 (Box 5)
    - Housing Opportunity for the Black and the Poor, 1971 (Box 5)
    - Guidelines for Mortgage Lenders, 1975 (Box 5)
    - Fair Housing Board Annual Report, 1979 (Box 5)
  - Hotels
    - Trends: Hotel Development, 1982 (Box 5)
  - Impact Estimation
    - Impact Estiimation Relationships, 1975 (Box 5)
  - Improvement
    - Long Range County Imrpovement Program, 1973 (Box 5)
    - Planning for Arlington's Future, 1975 (Box 5)
    - Long Range County Improvement Program, 1975 (Box 5)
  - Incinerator
    - Expansion Program, 1954 (Box 5)
  - Income
    - Income Characteristics: 1980 Census Highlights, 1980 (Box 5)
  - Industry
    - Industry, Present and Future, 1961 (Box 5)
  - Jefferson Davis Corridor
    - A Plan for Continuing Development, 1971 (Box 5)
    - Alternative Development Patterns, 1973 (Box 5)
    - A Five Year Plan, 1973 (Box 5)
    - Recommended Land Use Plan, 1977 (Box 5)
    - Traffic Analysis Report, 1982 (Box 6)
  - Labor
    - Labor Force Characteristics: 1980 Census, 1983 (Box 6)
  - Land Use
    - Economic Survey, 1951 (Box 6)
    - Economic Survey Summary, 1951 (Box 6)
    - Industrial Site Survey, VEPCO, 1953 (Box 6)
    - Report on Land Use and Zoning, 1954 (Box 6)
    - Study of the Potomac River Front, 1954 (Box 6)
    - Report #1: Master Plan Study, 1956 (Box 6)
    - Supplement: Master Plan Study, 1959 (Box 6)
    - Fiscal Aspects of Land Use (draft), 1957 (Box 6)
    - Fixcal Aspects of Land Use (final), 1957 (Box 6)
    - Industiral Land STudy, Part 3, Report #3, 1957 (Box 6)
    - Maps (6), 1959 (Box 6)
    - Industrial Site Survey, VEPCO, 1959 (Box 6)
    - Proposed General Land Use Plan (draft), 1960 (Box 6)
    - Proposed General Land Use Plan (final), 1960 (Box 6)
    - Proposed General Land Use Plan 2, 1961 (Box 7)
    - Land Use Plan - Proposed Changes in Commercial Properties, 1961 (Box 7)
    - Commercial Land Use Planning, 1962 (Box 7)
    - Arlington County Planning (AIA), 1971 (Box 7)
  - Lee-Glebe
    - Lee-Glebe Commercial District, 1958 (Box 7)
  - Lee Highway
    - West Commercial District, 1958 (Box 7)
    - East Commercial District, 1960 (Box 7)
  - Limited English Speaking Residents
    - Analysis of Arlington County Services, 1984 (Box 7)
    - Summary Report, 1984 (Box 7)
    - Catalog of Arlington County Services, 1984 (Box 7)
  - Master Plan
    - Plan for Arlington County, Virginia, 1930 (Box 7)
    - Prospectus and Work Program, 1956 (Box 7)
    - Employment, Report #3, Master Plan Study draft), 1957 (Box 8)
    - Pilot Plan (draft), 1958 (Box 8)
    - Pilot Plan (final), 1958 (Box 8)
    - Master Plan Studies: Open Space (draft), 1959 (Box 8)
    - Master Plan Studies: Development Districts (draft), 1959 (Box 8)
    - Open Space Report (draft), 1960 (Box 8)
    - Master Plan, Preliminary, 1960 (Box 8)
    - Summary of Master Plan, 1961 (Box 8)
  - Parkington-Ballston
    - Parkington Shopping Center Design, Traffic Quarterly, 1951 (Box 8)
    - Parkington: Ballston Area Retail Development (includes Templeman letter), 1979 (Box 8)
  - Pentagon City
    - Pentagon City, 1972 (OVERSIZE) (Box 8)
    - Pentagon City: Report to Arlington County Board, 1973 (1) (Box 8)
    - Pentagon City: Report to Arlington County Board, 1973 (2) (Box 8)
    - Physical Development 1, 1975 (Box 8)
    - Transportation Analysis, 1975 (Box 8)
    - Performing Arts Center Feasibility Study, 1984 (Box 9)
  - Pershing Drive-Lyon Park
    - Pershing Drive East - Lyon Park, 1959 (Box 9)
    - Pershing Drive East - Lyon Park (revised), 1960 (Box 9)
  - Planning Commission
    - Initial Correspondence, resolution, 1950s (Box 9)
    - Annual Report, 1971 (Box 9)
  - Planning Council, Nat'l Capitol Region
    - Report, 1953 (Box 9)
  - Planning Handbooks, Pamphlets
    - Arlington Catches Up! 1951 (Box 9)
    - Assessment & Appeal Procedure - Real Property, 1975 (Box 9)
    - Assessment & Appeal Procedure - Real Property, 1977 (Box 9)
    - Development Process - General, 1978 (Box 9)
    - Certificate of Occupancy, 1978 (Box 9)
    - Rezoning, 1978 (Box 9)
    - Subdivision Approval, 1978 (Box 9)
    - Site Plan Review, 1978 (Box 9)
    - Use Permit, 1978 (Box 9)
    - Variance, 1978 (Box 9)
    - Construction Permits & Inspection, 1978 (Box 9)
    - Guide to Arlington County Planning, 1983 (Box 9)
    - Handbook of Planning Terminology (no date) (Box 9)
  - Photo File Index (no prints, no negs) (Box 9)
  - Planning Office
    - Organization (draft), 1960 (Box 9)
  - Population
    - Population Study, 1943 (Box 9)
    - Population Report #2 1956 (Box 9)
    - Population by Census Tract and Dwelling Units, 1958 (Box 9)
    - Population and Development Policy Staff Report, 1960 (Box 9)
    - Population by Census Tract and Dwelling Units, 1960 (Box 9)
    - Preliminary Population & Housing Unit Count, 1960 (Box 9)
    - Final Population & Housing Unit Count, 1960 (Box 9)
    - Population and Housing - Census '70, (1971) (Box 9)
    - Household and Population - Report #1 1975 (Box 9)
    - Household and Population - Report #2, 1975 (Box 9)
    - Black Population, 1980 (Box 9)
    - Asian-Pacific Islander Population, 1980 (Box 9)
    - 1980 U.S. Census Highlights, 1982 (Box 10)
  - Playgrounds
    - Playground System Plan and Report, 1944 (Box 10)
    - Supplemental Report #2, 1944 (Box 10)
    - Improvement Program, 1947 (Box 10)
    - Gulf Branch Neighborhood Proposals, 1958 (Box 10)
  - Property Yard
    - Report on Property Yard, 1953 (Box 10)
  - Public Works
    - Storm Sewer Priorities, County Planning Engr., 1950 (Box 10)
    - Sanitary Sewer Sys. Master Plan, Arlington County Planning Commission, 1961 (Box 10)
    - Sanitary Sewers & Waste Water Disposal, Washington Metro Region, Wolman & Geyer, 1962 (Box 10)
    - Sanitary Sewers & Waste Water Disposal, Washington Metro Region, Summary Report, Wolman & Geyer, 1962 (Box 10)
    - Solid Waste Disposal Study, WashingtonMetro Region, Black & Veatch, 1966 (Box 10)
    - Metro WAshignton Area Water Supply Study, Corps of Engineers, 1978 (Box 10)
    - Arlington County Water Sys. Study, Montgomery Engineers, 1980 (1) (Box 10)
    - Arlington County Water Sys. Study, Montgomery Engineers, 1980 (2) (Box 11)
  - Real Estate Assessment
    - 1950 Property Assessment in Arlington County - A Board of Equalization? (Box 11)
    - Report on Proposed Department of Real Estate Assessment, 1952 (Box 11)
    - Analysis of Assessment Ratio Data, 1961 (Box 11)
    - Assessment of Real Estate in Arlington County VA, Prelim Report, 1961 (Box 11)
    - Report on Procedures and Valuations, 1978 (Box 11)
    - Department of Real Estate Assessments, Annual Reports, 1954-1960 (Box 11)
    - Department of Real Estate Assessments, Annual Reports, 1961-1965 (Box 11)
  - Real Estate Survey
    - Arlington-Alexandria Survey, 1940 (Box 12)
    - Large Scale Housing Projects: notes, correspondence, 1938-1940 (Box 12)
    - Arlington Forest, 1940 (Box 12)
    - Arlington Village, 1940 (Box 12)
    - Buckingham, 1940 (Box 12)
    - Colonial Village, 1940 (Box 12)
    - Glebewood Village, 1940 (Box 12)
    - Highlands, 1940 (Box 12)
    - Kenmore, 1940 (Box 12)
    - Westmont, 1940 (Box 12)
    - Westover, 1940 (Box 12)
    - Westover Hills, 1940 (Box 12)
    - Real Estate Agent Returns, 1940 (Box 12)
    - Real Estate Agent Lists, 1940 (Box 12)
  - Recreation and Open Space
    - Report to Recreational Advisory Committee, 1944 (Box 12)
    - Recreation and Open Space Study (draft), 1957 (Box 12)
    - Open Space in Arlington (draft), 1958 (Box 12)
    - Park and Open Space Inventory, 1973 (Box 12)
  - Residential Development
    - Trends in Residential Development, 1982 (Box 12)
    - Trends in Residential Development, 1984 (Box 12)
  - Retail Stores
    - Drug, Jewelry, Gift, Florist, Book, Camera and Hobby Stores, 1960 (Box 12)
  - Rosslyn
    - Rosslyn District, 1960 (Box 12)
    - Rosslyn Capital Projects Report, 1978 (Box 12)
  - Rosslyn-Ballston Corridor
    - Housing and Neighborhood Profile, 1973 (Box 12)
    - Community Facilities, 1974 (Box 12)
    - Goal and Policy Framework for Future Development (draft), 1975 (Box 12)
  - Shirlington
    - Shirlington Commercial District, 1959 (Box 13)
    - Shirlington Commercial District - Supplemental, 1959 (Box 13)
    - Shirlington Shopping Center Redevel. Plan, 1976 (Box 13)
    - Village at Shirlington - Site Access & Area Roadnet Analyses, 1982 (Box 13)
    - Village at Shirlington - Urban Design, 1982 (Box 13)
  - Shopping Centers
    - Shopping Centers, 1960 (Box 13)
    - Westover Shopping Center, 1958 (Box 13)
    - Williamsburg Shopping Center, 1958 (Box 13)
    - Washington and Lee Shopping Area, 1959 (Box 13)
  - Six-Year Plan
    - Preliminary Department Proposals, 1950 (Box 13)
    - A Six-Year Plan for Arlington (draft), 1950 (Box 13)
    - A Practical Approach to Local Long Range Planning, Address by Bertram M. Gross, 1950 (Box 13)
    - Six-Year Plan, Preliminary Report, 1950 (Box 13)
    - Six-Year Improvement Program (draft), 1951 (Box 13)
    - Arlington Looks Ahead, 1951 (with 2 supplements) (Box 13)
  - Statistics
    - Data File '84 (1984) (Box 13)
  - Streets
    - Major Thoroughfares & Collector Streets, 1941 (Box 13)
    - Major Thoroughfare plan, 1959 (Box 14)
    - Street Index, 1960 (Box 14)
  - Travel and Tourism
    - Travel Development Feasibility Study (Phases 1 & 2), 1974 (Box 14)
    - Arlington Visitors Program, Report, 1979 (Box 14)
  - Urban Renewal
    - Urban REnewal, miscellaneous papers, 1957-1958 (Box 14)
    - Urban Renewal, Arlington County Planning Commission, 1958 (Box 14)
    - Urban Renewal, Reports, 1961 (Box 14)
    - Urban Renewal, 1962 (Box 14)
  - Wilson Boulevard
    - West Commercial Area, 1958 (Box 14)
    - East Commercial District, 1959 (Box 14)
  - Zoning
    - Zoning District Map, 1938 (Box 14)
    - Master Zoning Plan (ordinance), 1948 (Box 14)
    - Study on Planning and Zoning, 1948 (Box 14)
    - Zoning Proposals at Arlington Towers, 1957 (10 photos, See APPENDIX) (Box 14)
    - Commercial Development & Zoning (prelim.), 1957 (Box 14)
    - Revised Sign Ordinance - Proposed Amendments, 1959 (Box 14)
    - "M-1" and "M-1" Dist. & Proposed Ord. Amendments, 1974 (Box 14)
    - Satellite Dish & Antenna Issues Related to Zoning, Technology and Information Services, 1986 (Box 14)
- Fire Department
  - Rules and Regulations
    - Fire Department Regulations, 1946 (Box 14)
    - Training Manual, 1953 (Box 14)
    - Manual of Rules and Regulations, 1958 (Box 14)
  - Manpower and Personnel
    - Fire Division Duty Schedule Study, 1962 (Box 14)
    - Critical Manpower Shortage, 1965 (Box 15)
    - Critical Response Manning Problems, 1965 (Box 15)
    - Management/Personnel Study, 1973 (Box 15)
  - Planning
    - Charges for Private Fire Protection, League of VA Municipalities, 1937 (Box 15)
    - Fire Improvement Program Report, 1954 (Box 15)
    - Fire Protection Program Report, 1954 (Box 15)
  - Services
    - Use and Abuse of the Ambulance, 1953 (Box 15)
    - Report on Arlington County, Virginia, National Board of Fire Underwriters, 1960 (Box 15)
    - Ad Hoc Committee on Arlington Fire Services, 1983 (Box 15)
  - Facilities
    - Fire Station Relocation, 1977 (Box 15)
- Civil Defense
  - Operations
    - Arlington County Civil Defense Corps Instructor's Guide, 1953 (Box 15)
    - Arlington County Civil Defense Corps - Civil Defense for Buildings, 1954 (Box 15)
    - Manual of Civil Defense for Buildings, 1955 (Box 15)
  - Planning
    - Northern Virginia Region Civil Defense Plan 1951-53 (Box 15)
    - Natural Disaster Plan for Arlington County, 1956 (Box 15)
    - Arlington County Civil Defense Plan, 1957 (Box 15)
    - Civil Defense Operational Survival Plan, 1959 (Box 16)
    - Northern Virginia Community Shelter Plan, 1968 (Box 16)
  - Newsclippings
    - Office of Civil Defense - Press Book #1 1953-60 (Box 16)
    - Office of Civil Defense - Press Book #2 1953-60 (Box 16)
  - Newsletter
    - Civil Defense News (scattered), 1963-65 (Box 16)
  - Directory
    - Directory of War Agencies in Arlington County VA, 1942 (Box 16)
  - Annual Reports
    - 1952-55 (Box 16)
    - 1956-60 (Box 16)
    - 1961-65 (Box 17)
- Human Services
  - History
    - Organization & Administration, Arlington County Health Department, Lecture, 1953 (Box 17)
    - A History of Arlington County Health Department, Glenn C. Hillery, GWU School of Med, 1957 (Box 17)
    - Arlington County Area Profile, Volunteer Services Study, Health & Welfare Council, 1963 (Box 17)
  - Administrative Documents
    - Manual of the Arlington County Health Department Lab, William A. Dorsey, 1944 (Box 17)
    - Policies Governing Collection of Fees, Arlington Health Department, 1949 (Box 17)
    - Policies & Procedures, Arlington County Health Department, 1953 (Box 17)
    - Management Survey of Department of Health, C. Corbett Long & Associates, 1953 (Box 17)
    - Outline of Residency Training in Public Health, Department of Public Health, 1958 (Box 17)
    - Organization, Program & Administration of Arlington County Department of Public Health, County Manager, 1960 (Box 17)
    - Ordinance Aspects of Public Health: Health Sanitation Program, address by Norbert Melnick, 1960 (Box 17)
    - A Five-year Projection for Arlington County Department of Health, County Manager, 1961 (Box 17)
    - Operation of Department of Public Welfare, Advisory Committee on Public Welfare, 1961 (Box 17)
    - Department of Human Resources, "One Door" to Serve Citizen Needs (draft), Advisory Committee on Health & Welfare, 1968 (Box 17)
    - Master Plan for Department of Human Resources, Vosbeck, Vosbeck, Kendrick, Redinger, 1972 (Box 17)
  - Annual Reports, Departmental
    - Fourth Annual Report, Arlington County Health Department, 1928 (Box 17)
    - Report of Arlington County Health Department, 1930 (Box 17)
    - Annual Reports, Arlington County Department of Health, 1932, 1937, 1938, 1939 (Box 17)
    - Annual Report of Arlington County Lab, William A. Dorsey, 1943 (Box 17)
    - Annual Report, Department of Public Welfare, 1945 (Box 17)
  - Health Care Delivery
    - Annual Report, Arlington Hospital, 1944 (Box 17)
    - Analysis of Public Welfare in Arlington County, French M. Clevinger, Jr, 1946 (Box 17)
    - The Social Survey of Arlington Co, VA, Community Council of Arlington, 1946 (Box 18)
    - Review of Health & Hospital Survey, Karl H. York, Arlington Hospital, 1947 (Box 18)
    - Survey of Local Unofficial Health Agencies in Arlington County, Department of Public Health, 1958 (Box 18)
    - Health Projection Supplement (nursing personnel), Arlington County Department of Health, 1961 (Box 18)
    - Health Projection Supplement Summary, 1962 (Box 18)
    - Arlington Hospital Cost/Reimbursement Study, Peat, Marwick, Mitchell & Co, 1969 (Box 18)
    - Arlington's Health Services & Facilities, Committee Report, 1970 (Box 18)
    - A Study of Ambulatory Care & Extended Care in Arlington County, MDC Health & Hospital Services, 1972 (Box 18)
  - Child Care & Education